你想让我给你开门么
Did you want me to open the doors?
给  给你  钥匙
Here-- Here you go. The keys.
拿着它们  把门打开
You take them. You open the doors,
你为什么说英语
Why you talk English, huh?
不  不  不
No! No, no, no! No!
第四季 第四集
S04E04:Bullet Points
赌博毁掉了我的人生
Gambling destroyed my life--
我  我的家庭  我爱的一切
me, my family, everything I loved.
就好像是一次抢劫  唯一不同的是  我就是那个窃贼
It was like a robbery, only I was the thief.
你用来证明它的故事
It's amazing, the stories you tell yourself
很精彩
to justify it--
那个欺骗你不要停手
the lies that lead you to just one more hand,
再转一次
one more spin,
多下一注的谎言
one more roll of the dice.
我们早就说好了
This is our deal, okay?
玛丽  不行
Marie, no.
你们什么都不用干  我是认真的
You guys are not lifting a finger. I mean it.
是的  我们会把吃的都带过去
Yeah, we're bringing everything, so--
别争了好么
This-- This is not up for debate, okay?
很好
Great.
亲爱的  现在别担心了好么
Now, sweetie, don't worry, okay?
我们不会提到账单的
We're not going to say one word about the bills.
我们就为了让大家都方便一些
We just want to bring everyone up to speed, okay?
好的  我们一会见
All right. I'll see you soon.
再见
Bye.
那么
So...
一切就在今晚
tonight's the night.
没有回头路了
No turning back.
好
Well...
好就行
Okay.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
首先我做好点值分配
Okay, so first I assign point values,
综合几家弃牌的影响
correlate to the effect of removal.
你要分对八么
You going to split the 8s?
斯凯勒  听我说好么
Skyler, please.
现在  根据著名的
Now, the mathematical principle,
凯利标准数学公式
known as the Kelly Criterion,
当然是由我自己改进之后
upon which I devised my own strategy
而不同于麻省理工的公式
not similar to the MIT system.
沃尔特  你不是给他们上课
Walt, you're not teaching them.
你不是想让我做到万无一失么
I thought you wanted me to be thorough.
就玩牌  别说这么多
Just play. You're taking too long.
什么  你不认为我有必要
What, you don't think it behooves me
把一切都解释清楚么
to be able to explain any of this?
你有必要专业一些  我是这个意思
It behooves you to be a pro, that's all I'm saying.
这都是假的  赶紧
That's the fiction, so chop-chop.
别催我
Don't chop-chop me.
沃尔特
Walt.
现在  我们都知道第一个决定
Now, we both know that the first decision
是对八的时候分牌还是弃牌
is whether or not to split or surrender on 8s.
分牌
Split 'em.
两对都不错
Good on both.
第二个决定是继续要牌还是不要
Next decision is whether to double down or not.
做决定吧
What you should be doing.
11点  好的  要牌
On 11, yes. Double.
这把牌
Okay, this hand over here,
18点
we have a soft 18.
最后的决定  继续要牌还是不要
The final decision is whether or not is to hit or to stand.
发牌
Hit it.
15点
Becomes a hard 15.
庄家有张9
Dealer has a 9.
我看到了
I see that.
发牌
Hit it.
好的  我们来看看我的牌
Okay, let's see what I got.
21点
And 21.
-该死  -没错
- Damn. - Yep.
好吧  这个
Okay, this--
这个最关键的是
The key thing to remember here
不是一把的输赢
is that it's not about any one hand.
而是每小时玩几把
The key is the number of hands per hour.
我们再来一次
Let's go again.
零  负一
Zero, minus 1.
好
Okay.
沃尔特
Walt.
我又不是不会玩
It's not as if I don't know how to play.
我对于如何数牌的造诣
I certainly more than understand
还是很深的
how to count cards.
我们还是继续吧  好么
Let's just keep going, okay?
不  你知道么  我在恢复阶段
No, you know what? I'm in recovery.
还记得吧
Remember?
我现在都不应该玩牌
I shouldn't even be playing.
这才是我们应该继续
You-- And that is the fiction
假装的事情
that we should be sticking to.
你知道么
You know what?
你说的对
You're right.
没错
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
我们要把每一步都计划好
Um, we're not leaving anything to chance.
好了  我们开始
All right, let's get started.
我这有很多
I've got a lot of, uh--
沃尔特
Walt,
我们还有很多的细节问题需要解决
we've got a lot of ground to cover.
这是什么
What is this?
我们要把谎编圆
We have to get our stories straight.
我们必须步调一致
We've got to be on the same page.
这是剧本
Is this a script?
要点
Bullet points.
Bullet points?
就和短篇小说一样
Like a novella.
这倒是挺聪明的
This is smart.
你真想编个准备不足  计划不完整
You really want to try to sell a DEA agent some ill-prepared,
漏洞百出的故事来让
half-assed, full-of-holes story
毒品管制局的探员相信我们突然就有钱买洗车场了么
about how we suddenly have enough money to buy a car wash?
我要都记下么
Am I supposed to memorize this?
-我们还要练习  沃尔特  -好
- We need to practice, Walt.  - Yeah.
我们需要字斟句酌
We need to be word-perfect.
还得合情合理
Within reason.
我们需要这个故事值得推敲  能引发同情
We need this story to be solid and sympathetic
最重要的是  能让人相信
and most of all completely believable.
你觉得你告诉玛丽的故事
From a story that you already told Marie
她还没跟汉克说么
and you think that she hasn't told Hank?
别开玩笑了  那可是玛丽啊
Ha! Come on. This is Marie we're talking about here.
不 她没说
No, she hasn't.
她真的没说
She hasn't.
汉克认为一切费用都是他的保险在支付
Hank thinks his insurance is paying for everything.
玛丽没告诉他
Marie's not telling him
是我们在帮他支付他的理疗账单
that we're paying his therapy bills,
我们也不会说
and neither are we.
那为什么这样呢
And why is that again?
你是认真的么
Really?
如果我们编出了这个赌博的故事
If we have the gambling story...
你收钱了么  沃尔特
Did you take money, Walt?
你还记得格雷琴和埃利奥特么
You remember Gretchen and Elliot?
因为我记得
Because I seem to recall
你宁肯去贩毒也不接受帮助
that you'd rather sell drugs than take help.
好吧
Fine.
玛丽会单独告诉汉克
Marie will tell Hank in her own time,
而我们要帮她把基础做好
and at least we'll have laid the groundwork.
在汉克和小沃面前坦白交代
And coming clean with Hank and Jun--
很明显  坦白交代
Appearing to come clean
对大家来说都是最好的
will be the best thing for everyone.
我们谈过这个问题了对吧
We talked about this, okay?
我们达成一致了
We agreed about this.
是的  没错  但那只是
Yes, we did. It's just--
什么
What?
算了
Never mind. Just--
好的
Okay.
我认为我们
So I really think
我们得好好演练一下叙述部分
we should tag team the narrative, okay?
一个人负责故事的一部分
We'll each be responsible for certain portions of the story,
这样你我分头叙述的时候
and then we can, uh, we can hand off
就不会出什么纰漏
so we don't leave anything out,
还能表现的自然真实
and it'll seem the most natural.
好了  从我听到
Okay, so I'm going to launch
我们将买下洗车场这个
with the exciting news
惊喜消息开始
that we are buying a car wash--
太好了
Yay.
汉克接下来可能会
The next logical question
问的问题就是
Hank will probably ask
"你从哪弄到的钱"
is "Where are you getting the money?"
我会回答
To which I'll say
"我们从头到尾的讲一讲"
"We want to tell you the whole story.
"很精彩
"It's a doozy,
所以别太惊讶"
so hold on to your hats."
你喜欢么
Do you like that?
当然
Sure.
这样做有两个好处
It accomplishes two things.
很简洁
It keeps it light
而且让他们有所期待
while letting them know to expect something big.
没错  确实很精彩
Yeah. No. It's a doozy.
好了
Okay.
不管怎么说  你从这开始接着我的说
Anyway, that's where you will take over,
从诊断开始  第一页到第二页
starting with your diagnosis, pages 1 and 2.
基本上
Okay, and it's-- it's pretty much
和真相差不多
going to run parallel to the truth,
虽然很简单
which makes it easier,
但是
but, um...
一定要强调癌症的问题
just make sure to really hit the cancer,
突出恐惧感和绝望的心态
really touch on the fear and despair.
提醒他们不要忘记
It's good to remind them
同时博得他们的同情
and to get their sympathy right off the bat.
我们要让他们明白
We want them to understand
你为什么会做这么蠢的事情
why you could do something so stupid.
这个完了之后
Now, after that,
是第三页和第四页
per pages 3 and 4,
在你说完
after you say...
"赌博成瘾
"Gambling became an addiction,
我已经没法控制了"
and I just couldn't control it."
-你看到了么  -看到了
- Do you see that-- - Yes.
就在那页中间  好的
...right there in the middle of the page? Okay.
我还提到了那次抢劫
Oh, and I put in that line about robbery.
就在那次匿名戒毒会上
You know, from the G.A. Meeting?
我觉得那个不错
I thought that was good.
接下来我会插话  谈谈它对我们婚姻的影响
So next I'll chime in about how it affected our marriage,
从困惑开始
uh, starting with the confusion,
欺骗
uh, the deceit,
为什么不告诉别人
why we couldn't tell anyone.
"对我的行为感到非常  非常惭愧"
"...terribly, terribly ashamed of my actions."
没错
Yeah.
俩"非常"
There's two "Terriblys"?
表现你的悔悟之情
It's supposed to show contrition.
可我是不会这么用词的
Well, I just wouldn't use that word.
我从来不说"非常"
I would never say the word "Terribly."
按你想说的来  行了么
Phrase it however you want, okay?
你又开始新话题了  现在
You're jumping ahead. Now--
我为什么感到惭愧
And why-- why am I so ashamed?
你非要我回答么
Do I really need to answer that?
我一直供养我们的家庭   过去是  现在也是
I was and am providing for our family.
我们就从刚才停下的地方继续吧
Let's just pick up where we left off.
我很脆弱  失去控制
I'm weak, and I'm out of control.
我是说  这一切说的我好像是个废物
I mean, this whole thing makes me look like crap.
这个故事必须要毫无保留  沃尔特
This has to be a warts-and-all story, Walt.
我们需要让别人相信的就是这个  你我都难过极了
That's how we'll sell it, and we both look bad.
是这样  那你是怎么难过的
Oh, well-- How do you look bad exactly?
我找找那个"我和我老板睡觉"这条在哪
Where is the "I slept with my boss" Bullet point?
我怎么找不到呢
I can't seem to find that anywhere.
对于一个靠制毒生活的  被解雇了的中学教师
For a fired schoolteacher who cooks crystal meth,
我得说你反映挺快的
I'd say you're coming out pretty much ahead.
我不喜欢这个
I don't like it.
我不喜欢小沃瞧不起我
I don't want Junior thinking less of me.
至少你赌钱赌赢了
At least you won at gambling.
我却是个贱人妈妈
I'm just the bitch mom
总是对你步步紧逼
who wouldn't cut you any slack.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
抱歉把你牵扯进来
I'm sorry that I put you through all of this.
这句怎么样
How's that sound? Hmm?
给我
Here.
两个"抱歉"
Two "Sorrys."
我想我们到第五页了
I believe we were on page 5.
那么  等你说完抱歉之后
So, after you say how very sorry you are--
当然  用自己的方式
in your own words, of course--
我们就快结束
we're almost to the end,
我说我为你能去
and I say how proud I am of you
参加那个十二步的恢复计划而感到骄傲
for joining a 12-step program,
然后这里  我认为我们就要
and-- and this is where I think we should enact
把我们的感觉表演出来
how we're feeling, you know?
只是一个建议
Just a-- Just a suggestion.
你应该懊悔的看着地板
You might look down on the floor with remorse.
怎么了  又不是认真的
What? You don't have to mean it.
你就低头  沃尔特  行么
You just stare down at your feet, Walt, okay?
然后  我就
Then, uh, I'm gonna--
我想的是抓住玛丽的手
I was thinking of taking Marie's hand
说点煽情的话
and saying something emotional
比如"能和你说出来真是太解脱了
like "It's such a relief to tell you.
"有这么强大的家庭
"We're just so glad we have a strong family
来互帮互助  共度难关
"To help us through this,
我们真是太高兴了"
that we can all support each other."
然后我可能会哭一下
And then maybe I'll tear up a little.
我也不知道
I don't know.
等到时候看情况吧
I'll just have to see what happens in the moment.
你会哭出来  就在那个时候
You're going to cry? On cue?
我说我不知道  可能会
I said I don't know. Maybe.
那你抹去眼泪的时候
When you dab your eyes, you going to do it
你打算用左手还是右手
with your right hand or your left?
-这只是个想法  -流一滴还是两滴
- It's just an idea.  - One tear? Two tears?
这个戏一定要做足
This has to be convincing,
特别是要让汉克相信
especially to Hank.
我要尽我可能做到最好  沃尔特
I'm doing the best I can here, Walt.
没错  我就是要做到万无一失
And yes, I'm thorough.
也许撒谎对我来说
Maybe lying doesn't come as easily to me
没有对你来说那么容易
as it does to you.
伙计们  请进
Hey! Guys! Come on in.
你好  见到你很高兴
Hi. Good to see you.
把她放到那  小伙儿
Put her there, you little punk.
很高兴见到你  汉克
Great to see you, Hank.
伙计  最近如何啊
Hey, buddy. How you doing?
快来看看我的小公主啊
Oh, look at my little princess.
越长越大了
She's getting big, huh?
也重了
And heavy, too.
我闻到的是真的食物吧
Whoa, is that actual food I'm smelling?
我也能吃上一顿地道的饭菜了
I might get an honest-to-God meal here for once?
你看上去真不错
You look good.
谢谢你  亲爱的
Thank you, sweetheart.
你的姨妈  玛丽  她长的挺美
Your aunt Marie, she's cute,
就是总是把水烧过了
but she could burn water,
你懂我的意思么
you know what I'm saying?
你还真是搞笑
You are so very hilarious.
带着男人们去看看你的石头收藏吧
Go show the boys your new rock collection.
我们去把东西准备好
We're going to get things organized.
是的  大约需要二十分钟
Yeah, it'll be about 20 minutes.
你还收藏石头
You have a rock collection?
是矿石收藏
It's a mineral collection.
就是一些小玩意
Uh, just a little something I--
你们想看看么  想看么
You guys want to see it? Want to see it?
当然  我们去看看
Sure. Let's go see it.
哦  让我来
Oh, hey, let me.
没事  我能行
Hey, it's all right. I got it.
来吧  伙计们  就在走廊头上
Come on, guys, it's down the hall here.
那边那块  叫蔷薇辉石
Now that one there, that's Rhodonite, okay?
是锰链硅酸盐
It's manganese inosilicate.
真棒
Cool.
为什么是粉色的
What-- What makes it be all pink like that?
那是锰的颜色
Well, that's the manganese part, okay?
氧化了  你知道  就和生锈了一样
It-- It oxidizes, you know, like rust.
没错  锰可以在负三到正七之间保持
Exactly. Manganese can have an oxidation state
氧化状态
of between -3 and +7,
颜色在紫  绿  蓝
which takes it through a range of colors--
的界限内变化
purple, green, blue.
但最稳定的状态是正二
But its most stable state is +2,
一般就是浅粉色
which is usually pale pink.
就是这么回事
So...
没错  他说的那一堆乱七八糟就是对的
Exactly. Whatever the hell he said.
不管怎么说  你明白了就行
Anyway, you, uh, you get the idea.
没错  很有意思
Yeah, it's, uh, interesting.
很有意思的东西
Interesting stuff, that.
真的
Really.
在这  把那个文件递给我
here. Give me that file, will you?
这个你可得看看
You got to check this out.
我一直在研究一些东西
I, uh, have been working on something here.
就提供一点咨询
Been a little, uh, little consulting--
帮阿尔布开克警局办案
you know, weighing in on a case for APD.
把那个放进去
Put that in, will you?
放到那里面去
Put that in over there.
汉克  这里面是什么  不会是尸体什么
Uh, Hank, what is this? It's not a dead body--
不不不  不是那些
No, no, no, no. Nothing like that.
你们  说真的  得看看
You guys-- Seriously, you got to check this out.
好东西  好了么
This is good. Ready?
开始了
Here we go on here.
看看这家伙
Look at this guy.
看呢
Look.
一艘飞船在等待
A ship is waiting
所有设备都准备完备
All systems are go
确定吗  控制系统不值得信赖
Are you Sure, Control is not convinced
但是电脑说
But the computer has the evidence
没必要放弃
No need to abort
倒计时开始
Countdown starts
伙计  这你可编不出来
Oh, man. You can't make this stuff up.
4  3  2  1
4, 3, 2, 1
地球在我们脚下
Earth below us
这是谁
Who is this?
这位  我的朋友们
That, my friends,
是阿尔布开克第一号全民公敌
is Albuquerque's public enemy number 1.
失重
...weightless
呼叫  呼叫
Calling, calling
能和你们说出来真是太解脱了
Such a relief to finally tell you.
有这么强大的家庭
We're just so glad
来互帮互助  共度难关
that we have a strong family to help us through this,
我们真是太高兴了
that we can all support each other.
我的天呐
Jesus.
我都不知道该怎么说
I don't even know where--
我了个去啊
Holy shit.
是啊
Yeah.
沃尔特・H・怀特
Walter H. White.
一个天赋被埋没的男人
Man of hidden talents.
老爸  你太牛了
Dad, you're such a stud.
你到底赢了多少
How much did you win exactly?
老爸
Dad?
我也没有一个具体的数字
I-- I don't think I have exact figures.
足够来
It's, uh, it's enough to--
当然  去税之后
uh, after taxes, of course--
买下洗车场的了
to buy the car wash.
也许还够
Maybe even pay for
支付两个孩子的大学学费
a couple of halfway reasonable college educations.
该死的  老爸  你为什么不玩了
Damn, Dad, why'd you quit?
我现在都能收到汽车作为生日礼物了
I can totally get a car for my birthday now.
对吧
Right?
儿子  我
Son, I'm...
对我的行为感到非常  非常惭愧
terribly, terrible ashamed of my actions.
我能离开下么
Would you excuse me, please?
我需要上个厕所
I need to use the restroom.
沃尔特
Walt?
抱歉  我
Oh. Sorry. I--
我还以为你在里面摔倒了
I thought you might have fallen in there.
没有  没有  我只是
Uh, no, no. I just, uh--
那里面可有很重要的东西
Hey, man, that was some big stuff back there.
是的  我们想坦诚一些
Yeah, we wanted to be thorough, so--
是啊  那确实是个好故事
Yeah, well, it's quite a tale.
说出来一定不是那么轻松吧
It couldn't have been easy to talk about.
你知道么  沃尔特  如果你
You know, Walt, if you...
你可以告诉我
you can always bend my ear, right?
我是说  如果你需要倾诉或者
I mean, if you ever need to talk or--
发泄
or just blow off some steam.
我就在这
I'm-- I'm here.
也去不了哪
Not going anywhere.
谢谢你  汉克
Thanks, Hank.
相同的话也送给你
Same goes for me, you know.
如果你有什么想给我发泄的
if you ever want to bounce anything off me.
比如说  案子的事  其他的事
I don't know, case work, anything, really.
有些事情  也许说出来
Sometimes just talking something through,
就有可能理出头绪
you know, really can make a difference.
我是说  我们说的绝对不是
I mean, we're definitely not talking,
那种小打小闹
you know, bathtub crank here.
这是一个大工程
This is a big-ass operation.
一周几百磅
You know, hundreds of pounds a week,
还可能更多
maybe more.
那么
So, uh...
这个人是谁呢  对他你了解多少
who is this person? What do you know about him?
除了他已经死了
Other than the fact that he's deader than a Texas salad bar
还收藏了一套不错的管弦乐器之外
and has a decent set of pipes?
他是我要找的人
I'd say he's my guy.
你要找的人
Your guy?
有个神秘人物
There's this, uh, mystery man
我追踪他
I've been, uh, chasing
将近一年了
for the better part of a year.
他做出的冰毒
Cooks the purest meth
是我和其他人见过最纯净的
that, uh, me or anyone else has ever seen.
名字叫海森伯格
Goes by the name of Heisenberg.
是的  名字很怪对吧
Yeah. Pretty weird, huh?
我  我查了一下
I-- I-- I looked him up.
那是一个物理学家  希特勒的手下
It, uh, it was one of these physicists-- one of Hitler's guys,
一个叫维尔纳・海森伯格的物理学家
a physicist named Werner Heisenberg.
很有意思是吧
Real cute, huh?
不管怎么说  我想到一个办法
Anyway, I figure with a handle like that,
我的人是个有点书呆子的人  无意冒犯
you know, my guy's got to be some sort of an egghead. No offense.
名字叫做
And here we go--
盖尔"汤姆少校"贝提格
Gale "Major Tom" Boetticher.
我就是想看看
Anyway, I-- I-- I just want to see
从化学角度上来看
if I'm, you know, not barking up the wrong tree
我是不是找对人了
chemically speaking.
就我的理解来看
Uh, as far as I can make out,
他写的是苯丙酮制毒法
he's writing about phenylacetone cook, right?
没错
Yeah.
没错  现在已经很少见了
Yeah. That's pretty rare these days,
但它确实能产出
but it-- it does jive
我一直在追查的蓝色冰毒
with the blue stuff I've been tracking.
"两勺无豆人造黄油
"2 sticks dairy free soy margarine,
三分之二杯原糖"
2/3 cup turbinado sugar"?
素食甜点的食谱
It's a recipe for vegan s'mores.
这上面什么乱七八糟的东西都有
Hmm. There's all kinds of crazy crap in there.
没错  就像
Yeah, like, uh, you know,
10大躺骑自行车
top ten recumbent bicycles,
室内堆肥技巧
indoor composting tips.
就在那个
All right next to the--
甲基苯丙胺化学合成法的旁边
the mother of, uh, of methamphetamine synthesis.
这个家伙
This guy was a, uh--
这小子真是有个性啊
man, he was a real character.
是啊  他真的是独特
Yeah, he seems, uh, unique.
给我  我给你  给你看点东西
Here, let me-- let me-- let me show you something.
给我  给我
Give it-- Give it.
在这儿
Right here at the, uh--
看题目
And here's the top.
上面写道"致W・W先生
It says, uh, "To W.W.
我的明星  我的完美偶像"
My star, my perfect silence."
W・W
W.W.
我是说  你觉得这是谁
I mean, who do you figure that is, huh?
伍德罗・威尔逊
Woodrow Wilson?
威利・旺卡
Willy Wonka?
沃尔特・怀特
Walter White?
你抓住我了
You got me.
W・W
W.W.
伙计  让我稍微看一下
Hey, man, let me see this...
我好像想起一点...
for a second because I think I remembered...
在这
Ah. Here.
没错
Yes.
就是这儿
Yeah.
"当我听完博学的宇航员的话
"When I heard the learn'd astronomer..."
每一次向天空望去
Learned. "And from time to time
"感受星星上
"Looked up in perfect silence
完美的平静"
at the stars."
这是沃尔特・怀特曼的诗
It's a poem by Walt Whitman.
你要的W・W
Your W.W.
你真是聪明
You frickin' braniac.
真是太聪明了
Ha. You frickin' braniac.
我一定是上学的时候翘了那节课
I must have skipped that day in school or something.
谁知道呢
I don't know.
我把自己给绕进去了
I've been chasing my tail about that one, you know?
你应该是对的
I bet you're right.
很高兴能帮上忙
Well, I'm glad I could be of help.
对  沃尔特・怀特曼是吧
Yeah. Walt Whitman, huh.
所以你怀疑这个叫盖尔的人
So, uh, you think this Gale person
就是你要找的海森堡
is your Heisenberg?
对  应该是吧  但不肯定
Yeah, I think so. I don't know.
我就想抓住这个人
G--, I wanted to get this guy.
看来你已经得偿所愿了
It looks like you did.
不  我的意思是亲自抓住他
No, I mean, you know, me personally.
我想亲自给他铐上手铐
I wanted to be the one to slap the handcuffs on him,
铐上那渣子
that kind of shit.
波沛・多伊尔对青蛙一号摇手
Popeye Doyle waving to Frog One.
我没记错的话
If I recall,
至少在第一部《法国贩毒网》里
at least from the first French Connection,
波沛・多伊尔就没真正抓住过他
Popeye Doyle never actually caught him.
我和老波沛差不多
Yeah, I guess me and old Popeye, huh?
总晚了那么一步
A day late and a dollar short.
那杀他的凶手呢
What about the person who killed him?
那是阿尔布开克警局的事了
APD's problem, not mine.
有线索吗
Any leads?
我兄弟提姆说
My buddy Tim says
他们采到些指纹  准备用来识别身份
he's got some fingerprints they're trying to ID,
还有个目击证人看到个嫌犯
and an eyewitness saw a person of interest.
或许能查到真凶
Might get lucky there.
我觉得有人知情
I guess somebody knows something.
他们最终会找到开枪的人
They'll track down the shooter eventually.
杰西
Jesse!
请借过
Excuse me.
天呐
Oh, my G--.
杰西
Jesse?
什么事
What's up?
我有话和你说  行吗
I need to talk to you, okay?
就现在
Now.
说吧
Go ahead.
你能先停一下吗  拜托了
Would you stop doing what you're doing, please?
等这个剃完了  还有下一个
When I'm done, yo, that dude's next.
搞什么鬼  怎么了
What the hell? What is wrong--
我有公事要谈
I have some business to discuss.
那就谈吧  天呐
So discuss. Jesus.
放开我
Let go of me.
警方正在调查盖尔的凶案
Gale's murder is being investigated.
废话
Uh, duh.
我得到可靠消息
And I have it on good authority
他们在罪案现场发现了指纹
that they found fingerprints at the scene.
不是我的
Not mine.
说完了吗
We done here?
没  还没完
No, we are not done here.
要是你的怎么办
What if they are yours?
你怎么这么确定
How can you be so sure?
因为我还在这里  没看见吗
Because I'm here, all right?
你连襟早就盯上我了
Your brother-in-law's got such a hard on for me
如果警察发现了我的指纹
that if the cops would have found my fingerprints--
警察要是在那地方五条街以内
The cops would have found my fingerprints
发现了我的指纹
within five blocks of that place,
早就把我带走了
they would have picked me up by now.
弹壳呢
What about the casing?
Or casings? How--
你对他开了几枪
How many times did you shoot him anyway?
杰西  你把弹壳捡起来了吗
Jesse, did you pick up the casings?
捡起来了吗
Did you pick them up?
没
No.
听着  我们得一步步来
Listen, uh, we've got to go over this
重现当时的一切情景
step by step-- everything.
你得告诉我从你到那里开始
I want you to tell me exactly what happened
确切的事发经过
from the moment you got there.
我进去又出来了
I got in, I got out.
不  不  我要知道细节
No. No, I need to know specifics.
现在我们从头说起
Now, we'll start from the beginning.
你开车过去  你开车过去
You-- You drove there. You drove over there.
冲着他家门走去  对吗
You went to his door, right?
杰西  我要你全神贯注
Jesse, I need you to concentrate.
事关重大
This is very important.
你是敲门了还是按门铃了
Did you knock or ring?
敲门还是按门铃
Knock or ring? Uhh!
敲门
Knock.
好  很好  非常好
Okay, good. That's very good.
仔细听好
Now listen.
设想盖尔应了门
I assume that Gale answered the door.
然后呢
Now what happened after that?
他认出你来了吗
Did he recognize you?
你们对话了吗
Did you say anything to each other?
你进门了吗
Did you walk into the room,
还是当场就开枪杀了他
or did you shoot him right then and there?
怎么了
What?
谁想赚一百块
Who wants to make a hundred bucks?
听着  这孩子可能没说错
Look, the kid's probably right.
要是警方有证据
If they had anything on him,
早就把他关起来了
he'd be locked up already.
那我的连襟呢
What about my brother-in-law?
他怀疑杰西
He suspects Jessie。
不知怎么  他就知道杰西
How, he knows Jesse is involved
也参与蓝色冰毒的贩卖了
in the sale of blue meth.
那是汉克唯一的线索
That was Hank's one and only lead.
要是他把这些线索联系起来
Now what if he puts 2 and 2 together
从杰西这条线索查这起凶案呢
and he goes after Jesse for the murder?
怎么查  靠他的杂牌小车吗
He goes after him how, on his Rascal Scooter?
可能有点过
Ahem. That, perhaps, sounded insensitive.
可如果他查他的话
Uh, but if he goes after him,
我就告他治安粗暴
I'll sue his ass for police brutality,
骚扰  攻击  还有其它16项罪名
harassment, assault, and 16 other things.
现在拿两个人的纠葛已经发展到
Now, the history that those two have together
现在这个样子
being what it is,
你得认为你的连襟
you got to figure your brother-in-law's
足够聪明  不从这条线索追查下去
smart enough not to go down that particular road.
零蛋
Goose egg, bupkis--
那帮警察就得到了这个了
that's what the cops got.
我不会操那份心
I wouldn't worry about it.
我还有什么事不用操心的  索尔
What else should I not worry about, Saul, hmm?
我是不是也不用担心古斯一逮到机会
Should I not worry that Gus plans to murder me
就要杀我
at the first chance he gets?
我是不是也不用担心我吸毒成性的搭档
Should I not worry that my drug-addicted partner
无所谓自己的死活
doesn't seem to care whether he lives or dies?
你该看看他的房子
You should see his house.
和贫民窟没两样
It's-- It's like Skid Row.
一堆流浪汉住在那里
He has actual hobos living there.
现在离古斯觉得他是个大麻烦
Now how long before Gus decides
还有多远
that he's too big of a risk?
那个麦克
Geez, that Mike,
那个总犯嘀咕有眼无珠的白痴
that grunting dead-eyed cretin
冲我脸上就是一拳
sucker-punching me in the-- in the face.
我看到古斯挥舞着切割机
I've got Gus wielding a box cutter.
我是说  我收到讯号了
I mean, Western Union-- message received.
这...
It--
我问你
Let me ask you.
这什么时候不是桩买卖了
When did this stop being a business, hmm?
为什么只有我
Why am I the only person
可以表现得像个专业人士
capable of behaving in a professional manner?
不  我...
No, I--
不  无论你从哪方面考虑  谁都有危险
No, any way you slice it, everyone's in danger.
我怎么才能保护大家
I mean, how-- how can I protect anyone?
我的亲人  杰西  我自己
My family, Jesse, myself?
我的名字没有就入选  对吗
My name never comes up with those guys, does it?
与此同时  我们还要买这家该死的洗车店
Meanwhile, we're buying this stupid car wash.
对  木已成舟
Oh. Yeah. That ship has sailed.
一路平安
Bon voyage.
我们已经付诸实践了
We are committed.
我们已经告诉家人这个决定了
We already told our family about it,
现在斯凯勒肯定相信
and now Skyler, I'm sure she believes--
她得相信
she needs to believe
一切尽在掌握
that everything is neat and tidy,
她正在心理暗示
and she's telling herself
我在一家漂亮而安静的小实验室工作
that I work in this nice quiet little lab
穿着白大褂  带着袖珍保护装置
with a white lab coat and a pocket protector
我的合同一到期
and when my contract is up
我就只要卸下装备
I'll just simply hang it all up,
摘下帽子  打道回府
tip my hat, and walk away.
天呐
Oh, God.
事情怎么都搞得一团糟了
How did everything get so screwed up?
对  你的确有太多烦心事了
Yeah, you do have a little shit creek action happening.
仅供参考  你可以买个保险
You know, FYI, you can buy a paddle.
这是以防万一的最后一招
This is a last resort back pocket kind of thing,
但你如果真想自保
but if you really got to protect yourself,
就消失吧
uh...disappear.
人间蒸发
Poof.
Poof?
有个人能帮你们
There's a guy who can make it happen.
就叫他
Call him a, uh...
消失达人吧
disappearer.
需要丰厚的酬劳  得非常丰厚
For a substantial fee, and I do mean substantial,
你和你爱的人可以人间蒸发
you and your loved ones can vanish, untraceable.
他可以帮你们开始崭新的生活
I mean, he sets you up with a whole new life.
什么
What, like a...
就像证人保护计划那种吗
witness protection kind of thing?
比那还高端  完全不会被查到
Beyond. I mean, off the grid.
有新的身份  新的一切
New identities, new everything.
没人能追踪到你们的行踪
No one would ever be able to trace you.
现在得说清楚  这是终极法宝
Now, be clear, this is an end game,
如果你懂我的意思
if you get my meaning.
没有后悔药吃
I mean, there's no coming back.
你要他的名片吗
You want his card?
天呐  真希望我还有其它选择
God, there's got to be something else that I could do.
找到能让一切都回到正轨的方法
Some way to keep everything from spiraling out of control.
根据你的叙述
Well, I mean, from what you told me,
平克曼将第一个
it sounds like, uh, Pinkman is first up
步入死亡的殿堂
in the imminent demise department.
古斯不会让警方有机会找到杰西的
Gus won't risk letting the police find Jesse.
我知道 他不会让警方有机会的
I know him, he won't
不是我说啊  你们好好想想
I am not even kindding because if you really think about it.
你都看不到  又怎么知道无线电波
You can't even see it. So how can you know just how bad
微波和手机对你产生什么伤害呢
radio frenqueces and microwaves and cellphones this stuff are giving you
也许你去奶奶家
I mean, you could be strolling security of the airpirt
过机场安检的时候
On the way to visit your grandma.
起来了
Wake up bitches!
你会被要求过全身扫描
And then you get wave through a whole body scanner
然后转天你不死也会奄奄一息
And next day you could be dead or dying.
至少是被辐射的奄奄一息了
At least dying fron all the radiation
绝对不是他们所说的对身体无害
that they say is safe, but there's no way
因为辐射浓度很高
Because they have to deliver a concentrated dose, okay?
辐射量足够可以穿透衣服
Enough to penetrate through clothes
日积月累对易受感染的人绝对是个威胁
So the accumulated amount of is definitely dangerous to susceptible individual
尤其是那些从乡下来的人
especially if you from a rural area
我说  老兄
Hey，yo!
臭氧层本来就因为
and the ozone layer's already thin
那些牛放的屁而薄了许多
Because of the cow farts.
我说
Yo
是你啊
Hey.
在我回来之前买好比萨啊
Will you make sure there is pizza here when I get back?
没问题吧  要够大伙吃
All right? Enough for everybody.
没问题啊
I could do that.
我肯定能买
I could definitely do that.
绝对没问题
Not a problem
我能买来  比萨什么的
I can get the stuff, the pizza and the stuff.
但我没多少钱了
But as far as the financial situation you know
等下
Just hanging on
跟你说啊
You know
高剂量的辐射
The concentrated doses is gonna
会对骨髓造成伤害
gonna play hob your bone marrow.
然后还会搅乱...
and it's really gonna mess up...
尤其是如果你有癌症的话
Because--because especially if you have cancer.
还必须要做一个骨髓移植
You know cause if you got to get a bone marrow transplant
也就是...百分之六十
You're odds are...you are 60%...
你也就有百分之六十的机会
you have 60% chance.
再买点面包条
Get some dipping sticks, too
我肯定能买来
I can definetely get dipping sticks.
我能买来的
All right, I can get them.
都给我吸了吧  贱人们
Suck it up. bitches.
起来
Wake up.
怎么了
What's up.
你耳朵怎么了
What's up with your ear?
现在下楼
Downstaris now.
人都哪去了
Where is everybody?
我把你的朋友都请走了
I invited your guests to leave.
知道这人是谁吗
You know who this is?
不知道
No
你应该知道的  他在你家呆了3天
You ought to, he spent at your house for 3 solid day.
然后呢
Ok?
他偷了你的钱
He stoled your money.
然后呢
Ok?
这7万8看着眼熟吗
That 78000 still looks familar?
-就这个  -是的
- This is it?   - That's it
好的
Ok
谢了
Thanks
你想知道接下来我会
You wanna know what's next?
怎样对待尿裤子先生吗
for little Miss pissed in his pants
不想
No
你确定
You're sure no?
连猜都懒得猜
Don't even wanna take a wild guess.
你要杀了他
You are gonna kill him.
我现在是不是该要求你不要杀
This is the part where I am supposed to beg you not to do it?
求求你了
Please...please.
然后呢
And then what?
我是不是应该发誓说
I am supposed to promise cross my heart.
每天都准备好听你们的命令行事
to, like, straighten up and fly right or toe the line
或者其他什么屁话
Some other carp that I am not gonna say.
这就是你演这出戏的目的
Is that what your liitle show here was all about?
你已经如履薄冰了  小子
You are on thin ice, you little shit head,
懂吗
You know that?
你不会杀了他的
You ain't gonna smoke that dude in there.
知道我怎么知道的吗
You know how come I know?
因为你费周折蒙上了他的眼睛
Cause you went to the trouble put a blind fold on him.
我继续睡觉了
I am going back to bed .
你愿意干嘛就干嘛
Knock yourself out.
抱歉久等了
I am sorry to keep you waiting.
耳朵好了吗
How's the ear?
还在养伤
Mending.
有事吗
What can I do for you?
是平克曼的事
It's Pinkman
他越来越不谨慎了
He's becoming increasingly incautious.
是个不稳定因素  会拖我们后退
He's a risk, a liability.
我知道他和沃尔特是搭档
I know he and Walter comes as a team
这么做沃尔特估计不会高兴
and Walter won't like it.
但是我们应该采取点措施了
But something gotta be done.
是我
Hey, it's me,
是我  听到提示后留言
wait for the thing.
我去
Right
这是第三条留言了
This is message No.3
你最好两分钟内收拾好
You'd better be ready in 2 minutes.
因为我已经在你家门口了
because I am right out side your door.
杰西
Jesse.
妈的
Damn it!
是我  听到提示后留言
Hey, it's me, wait for the thing.
受不了
Great.
杰西
Jesse.
真是受不了了
This is perfect.
你真是一极品  知道么
You are a piece of work, you know that?
杰西
Jesse.
是我  听到提示后留言
Hey, it's me, wait for the thing.
他在哪
Where is he?
不问问我们去哪里么
Gonna ask where we are going?
不
Nope.